Welcome back to Jupyter Lab.
주피터 연구소에 잘 오셨어요
Last time, we looked at some silly models for predicting the price of products to make our basic,
지난 시간에는 바보 같은 모델을 살펴봤죠 제품의 가격을 예측해서 기본 기준을 설정하는
basic baselines.
방법이었죠
Now we're going to look at some more interesting baseline models.
이제 좀 더 흥미로운 기본 모델을 살펴보죠
This of course, again is the diagram showing you that very simple model of predicting a flat average
이건 물론 도표입니다 아주 간단한 모델로 평평한 평균 가격을 예측할
price.
수 있죠
You may notice a tiny, tiny change here, which is that I've changed the color, the yellow color that
여기서 아주 작은 변화가 보이실 겁니다 제가 색을 바꿨죠 원래 여기 있던 노란색이 더 보기
was here into a more pleasing orange color because I think the yellow is harder to see.
좋은 주황색으로 바뀌었어요 노란색이 잘 안 보이거든요
But otherwise this should be a familiar picture for you.
하지만 그렇지 않다면 익숙한 사진일 거예요
And you'll notice that on average, it's out by $145.
평균적으로 145달러가 빠져나갔어요
I should mention that when we looked at the the prior diagram, I'm not sure if I looked at this if
앞서 다이어그램을 봤을 때 말씀드리고 싶은 게 있는데 이걸 봤는지 모르겠는데
I showed this to you, but on average that was out by $340.
평균적으로 340달러나 차이가 나요
So considerably worse performance, if you guess randomly than if you take an average, for obvious
즉, 평균보다 무작위로 추측하면 상당히 나쁜 결과가 나온다는
reasons.
거죠
Uh, because yeah, obviously, because the data set isn't, uh, evenly distributed.
네, 물론 데이터 세트가 균등하게 분배되지 않았기 때문이죠
It's uh and Nord is it's average 500.
노드는 평균 500달러예요
Uh, okay.
네
So now let me at this point, uh, we're going to move to the topic of feature engineering, which is,
그럼 이제 이 시점에서 기능 공학으로 넘어가겠습니다 전통적인 머신
uh, one of the most fundamental of the traditional machine learning techniques.
러닝 기술의 가장 근본적인 것 중 하나죠
And frankly, it's the way that data science used to work.
데이터 과학이 예전에 쓰던 방식이죠
This is what we would do.
우리라면 이렇게 했을 거예요
Uh, when this kind of problem came up, you would start trying to think about what are the aspects
이런 문제가 발생하면 이런 문제를 해결할 양상은 무엇인지 생각해
of this problem, what are the aspects of each product from Amazon that would be most suitable to use
보게 됩니다 아마존 제품의 각 제품에서 가격을 예측하는 데 가장 적합한 양상은
to try and predict the price?
무엇인지 말이죠
And a lot of time was spent trying to to do what people call feature engineering, which is figure out
기능 엔지니어링이라는 걸 하려고 많은 시간을 들였어요 특정 아이템의 어떤
what properties of a particular item are most meaningful to predict its price.
속성이 가격을 예측하는 데 가장 중요한지 알아내는 거죠
And people used to spend lots of time working on that before we found that deep neural networks can
심층 신경망이 그 모든 걸 가능하게 하기 전까진 많은 시간을
do all of that for you.
투자했죠
So anyways, uh, what we're going to do now is work on feature engineering and I should say one more
어쨌든, 이제 기능 공학에 대해 공부할 겁니다 다시 한 번 말하지만 기능 공학이나
time that sometimes feature engineering and traditional machine learning will perform great.
전통적인 머신 러닝이 훌륭하게 작동할 때도 있어요
Sometimes that is what your problem needs.
가끔은 그게 문제가 될 수도 있어요
And you may think that in the case of an Amazon product, we're in that kind of territory.
아마존 제품의 경우 우리가 그런 영역에 있다고 생각할 수도 있어요
Uh, but we'll we'll see how it performs.
하지만 성능은 봐야죠
So first of all, let me remind you of something.
먼저 한 가지 상기시켜 드리죠
If I look at one of my training data points, uh, you may remember this.
제 훈련 데이터를 보면 기억하실 거예요
There is a field called details.
디테일이라는 게 있어요
That was one of the fields that we sucked from our Amazon data set.
아마존 데이터 세트에서 우리가 빨아들인 필드 중 하나예요
Um, and what this is, it looks a bit like a, like a Python dictionary.
이건 파이썬 사전처럼 생긴 비트인데요
At first blush.
언뜻 보면요
You're seeing keys and values.
키와 가치가 보이죠
Uh, but then you'll notice that the whole thing is, in fact, a string.
그러면 전체적인 것이 문자열이라는 것을 알 수 있죠
Uh, it's all one big string.
하나의 큰 문자열이죠
It's a JSON blob representing a dictionary.
사전을 나타내는 JSON 블롭이에요
Uh, so it would be nice if we could read in this details field on every one of our data set points
이 상세 필드를 읽을 수 있다면 좋을 것 같아요 트레이닝과 테스트에서 모든 데이터
in training and in test and convert it from being text into being a Python dictionary.
세트 포인트를요 그리고 텍스트에서 파이썬 사전으로 전환하는 거죠
And luckily, the standard library gives us a way to do that.
다행히 표준 라이브러리가 그걸 가능하게 하죠
Using the JSON package, we can do Json.loads or Loadstring and it will convert these strings into objects.
JSON 패키지를 이용해 JSON을 할 수 있어요 Loadstring을 하면 이런 문자열을 개체로 변환하죠
So we're going to run that and then we'll we'll run that.
그걸 실행하고 그걸 실행할 거예요
It will just take a few seconds.
몇 초면 돼요
And then now what I can now do is say train zero dot features.
이제 트레인0.com 특징을 입력할 수 있어요
And we'll expect to see this same string but now converted into a Python dictionary.
그리고 이 문자열이 파이썬 사전에 변환된 걸 보게 될 거예요
Let's see.
어디 보죠
Let's run that.
실행해 보죠
There we go.
됐어요
You can see that.
보면 알잖아요
Sorry.
미안해요
As I zoom around a dictionary and you can see that it's the same as that text.
사전을 확대해 보면 그 텍스트와 같은 걸 볼 수 있죠
And in fact we can do dot keys and see its keys are right here.
.키를 입력하면 여기 키가 있는 게 보이죠
Now there's a problem with our data, which is that turns out these dictionaries are populated differently
우리 데이터에 문제가 있어요 이 사전들은 다른 제품들에 대해 다르게 채워져 있다는
for different products.
거죠
Some products don't have any, uh, any features at all.
어떤 제품은 기능이 전혀 없어요
Some of them have, um, just, uh, sparse, uh, features.
어떤 건 특징이 거의 없어요
So, so it's inconsistently populated.
일관성이 없는 포집이죠
Let's get a sense of that.
get get get을 해 보죠
We can use another useful Python standard library, uh, tool, the counter, um, in the collections
또 다른 유용한 파이썬 표준 라이브러리 도구를 사용할 수 있습니다 컬렉션 패키지에서 counter를요
Uh, and what you can do with the counter is you can count things up, and then you can say things like,
counter로 할 수 있는 건 숫자를 세는 겁니다 그런
uh, feature count, dot most common and asked to see the most common 40 of these.
다음 기능 카운트, 가장 흔한 것 .40 같은 걸 말할 수 있죠 가장 흔한 걸 보여달라고 요청하는 거예요
So let's run that and you'll see what comes back.
실행해보죠 뭐가 나오는지 보세요
So what we're seeing here is what are the most common, uh, 40 features that are populated against
가장 일반적인 기능은 40개입니다 모든 훈련 데이터 포인트에 대항해
all of our training data points.
채워져 있죠
Uh, and so date first available is populated a lot.
날짜 먼저 사용 가능은 많이 채운다는 거죠
Uh, almost.
거의요
Uh, yeah.
네
90% of our, of our population has that populated, uh, it's, what, 360,000 of the 400,000 that we
인구의 90%가 데이터 집합에 있는 400,000명 중 360,000명 정도에
have in the data set.
해당하죠
Uh, item weight is very well populated.
품목의 무게는 아주 많이 차 있어요
Manufacturer brand.
제조사 브랜드예요
They're quite similar bestsellers.
비슷한 베스트셀러예요
Rank is also well populated and then it starts to tail off.
랭크도 가득 찼다가 사라지기 시작하죠
So what are good candidates for us to use for features?
그럼 어떤 특징을 사용하면 좋을까요?
Well, we're really looking for something that's well populated.
많이 들어찬 걸 찾고 있어요
That's a good start.
시작이 좋네요
We want it to be consistently populated, and we also want it to be something that feels like it's likely
지속적으로 채워지길 원하고 가격과 의미 있게 연관될 가능성이
to be meaningfully related to the price.
있는 뭔가가 되길 원해요
And so looking at these item weights, that feels like it's a pretty solid candidate.
이 아이템의 무게를 보면 꽤 확실한 후보 같아요
Like you think that that that I mean, it's not clear, but probably there's some correlation some of
당신 생각에는 확실하진 않지만 무게와 가격 사이에 상관관계가
the time between weight and price.
있을 거예요
Uh, you know, like a bigger, heavier thing, maybe more valuable on average, uh, brand seems like,
더 크고 무거운 제품이나 평균적으로 더 가치 있는 제품요 브랜드가 기능과 정확히
uh, obviously it's not going to, to exactly match with a feature, but maybe there's a way that we
일치하진 않겠지만 베스트셀러 순위에 들 수
can make it and maybe best sellers rank.
있는 방법이 있을 거예요
That could be something.
중요한 단서일 수도 있어요
That's something that's a bestseller might do well.
베스트셀러로 잘 팔릴 것 같아요
So we'll start with those.
이것부터 시작하죠
Those feel like they are reasonable features to begin with.
이런 것들은 처음부터 합리적인 기능으로 느껴졌어요
And we'll add on one more thing that just is a throwback to something we talked about a while ago.
한 가지만 더 추가할게요 아까 얘기했던 것으로 되돌아가는 거죠
Um, so I'm going to start with something that's a bit janky.
약간 조잡한 비트부터 시작할게요
As I put here, this is a this is a little bit hokey.
여기 비트를 보면 좀 진부해요
Uh, so it turns out that the weight that's populated in this dictionary is just like, very, uh,
이 사전에 채워진 무게는 아주 더러운 데이터예요
In some cases, it's in pounds, in some cases it's in ounces, in some cases it's in hundredths of
파운드 단위로도 나오고 온스 단위로 나오기도 하고 100g 단위로
pounds and a milligrams and kilograms and various other things.
나오기도 해요 1mg이나 킬로그램 등 다양하죠
So I've just got a big old if statement here that goes through, figures out what units is this weight
여기 if문이 있는데요 어떤 웨이트 단위를 입력했는지
in, and converts it all to a number of pounds and returns that amount.
알아내고 파운드로 변환한 다음 그 양을 반환하죠
So that's what this is.
그런 거였군요
I'm not going to necessarily convince you that this does the job.
이게 효과가 있다는 걸 꼭 설득할 필요는 없어요
You could take my word for it.
내 말을 믿어요
Or if you distrust me, Then come on in and try it out for some of these.
아니면 날 못 믿겠으면 들어와서 이걸 써봐요
Um, and, uh, yeah, I then I'm going to get all of the weights for all of my training items.
그리고 제 운동 기구에 쓸 웨이트도 전부 get 할 거예요
Um, and, uh, this line here, uh, if isn't obvious, filters out any, any nones from there so that
그리고 이 선은 0을 걸러내는 거예요 단위를 인식하지 못하는 게 있으면
because I return none if there's something that I, that I don't recognize the units for, um, and
0을 반환하기 때문에 훈련 데이터 집합의 평균
that allows me to calculate the average weight of all of our training data set.
무게를 계산할 수 있어요
The average weight is £13.6.
평균 체중은 13파운드예요 6개요
Uh, now you may say, why do I need to calculate the average weight?
왜 평균 무게를 재야 하냐고 하실 수도 있겠네요
Well, it's for a slightly technical reason that when we're dealing with this kind of linear regression,
약간 기술적인 이유에서죠 이런 선형 퇴행 과정을
you have to make some decisions about how are you going to handle the items which don't have a weight
다룰 때는 중량 인구가 없는 아이템을 어떻게 다룰지 결정해야
populated the 10% of our items of our training set that doesn't have a weight.
합니다 훈련 아이템 중량 없는 10%를요
And there are various techniques you can use, uh, people, data scientists amongst you probably know
다양한 기법을 사용할 수 있어요 데이터 과학자들도
that you can do some tricks where you you have a feature which represents whether or not there is a
알 텐데 하중이 있는지 없는지를 나타내는 기능을 활용할 수 있어요
And then you have to do some, some jiggery pokery with how you incorporate that in your model.
그리고 모델의 몸에 그걸 어떻게 적용할지 어설프게 표현해야 해요
Um, and one approach that's a perfectly respectable approach is to say if something doesn't have a
완벽하게 신뢰할 수 있는 접근법이 하나 있는데 무게가 없는
weight, just pick the average and plonk that in there.
건 평균을 골라서 집어넣는 거예요
And so I have this function get weight with default, which takes an item, it tries to get its weight,
기본값으로 함수 get-tier를 설정했는데 항목을 취하고 그 가중치를 얻으려 하죠
and it either returns the weight or if the weight is none or zero, because that's presumably a problem.
가중치를 반환하거나 가중치가 없거나 0이면요 문제가 될 테니까요
If something has no weight, then we swap it out for an average weight instead.
무게가 없는 건 평균 무게로 바꿔요
Uh, so that is the get weight with default.
기본값 get 웨이트고요
I think this was a fair amount of, uh, grotty work as we do our feature engineering.
기능 공학에서 꽤 지저분한 작업이 되었어요
So I'm going to take a break, let you mull over the other features we've got to do.
잠시 쉴 테니 다른 기능들을 잘 생각해 보세요
And when we come back, we're going to go into best sellers rank before wrapping up feature engineering
잠시 후에는 베스트셀러 순위에 오르겠습니다 기능 엔지니어링과 모델을 실행하기
and running our model.
전에요
And seeing how it predicts prices.
가격 예측도 하고요
See you in a second.
이따 봐요